《黑镜》
《圣朱尼佩罗》
贝琳达·卡莱儿带来的1987年至今最热单曲
Belinda Carlisle there with one of the biggest hits of 1987 so far.
相信你们会爱上这首歌的 我们马上回来
Gotta love that track! Coming up next in just a moment…
能不能别闹了 我只想找点乐子好吗
Could you please stop it? I just wanna have some fun, okay?
凯丽 别这样
Kelly, come on.
- 凯丽 - 我在走路看不见吗
- Kelly. - I'm still walking, Wes.
我们只剩几小时了 别浪费啊
We've only got a couple of hours so let's, uh… let's use it.
我没有浪费啊
I am using it.
∮ 找了份工作 倒还凑合 ∮
∮ Got a job, that's okay ∮
∮ 就是得日夜工作 ∮
∮ But they've got me workin' night and day ∮
∮ 打卡上班 打卡下班 ∮
∮ Punching in, punching out ∮
∮ 这难道就是工作的所有意义吗 ∮
∮ Is this really what it's all about? ∮
∮ 你将来要做什么 会有如何感受 ∮
∮ What you gonna do, what you gonna feel? ∮
∮ 我不知道 ∮
∮ I don't know ∮
∮ 你会如何感受 你将来要做什么 ∮
∮ What you gonna feel, what you gonna do? ∮
∮ 谁来告诉我 ∮
∮ Won't someone tell me? ∮
∮ 你要说什么 你要做什么 ∮
∮ What you gonna say, what you gonna do? ∮
∮ 只有一件事可以说 ∮
∮ There's only one thing left to say ∮
∮ 这就是生活 这就是生活 ∮
∮ C'est la vie, c'est la vie ∮
∮ 生活本就如此 ∮
∮ That's just the way it goes ∮
∮ 没错 ∮
∮ That's right ∮
∮ 这就是生活 这就是生活 ∮
∮ C'est la vie, c'est la vie ∮
嗨
Hey.
你很擅长这个嘛
You're good at this.
它 呃 有不同的结局
It's, uh… got different endings.
取决于你是一个人还是两个人玩
Depending on if you're in one or two player.
嗯哼
Uh-huh?
- 这是第一个有如此设定的游戏 - 该死
- It was kinda the first game to do that. - Damn it!
你想玩极速吗
Do you wanna play Top Speed?
噢 不了
Oh, no.
谢谢你 我只想自己熟悉熟悉
Thank you. I just wanna get my bearings a bit.
呃 好吧
Uh… okay.
- 待会见 - 嗯
- See you around? - Mm-hmm.
对我说的所有话你都要表示赞同
Go along with whatever I say.
- 什么 - 不管我说什么 你赞同就好了
- Sorry? - Whatever I say, go along with it.
好吧 韦斯 你现在只是在纠缠我
Okay, Wes, you're just pestering now.
- 真的要我亮红灯举报你吗 - 两小时三十五分钟
- Do I have to red light you? - Two hours 35.
- 没什么时间了 - 韦斯
- There's not much time left. - Wes.
听着
Look…
- 上周 我们那么棒的 - 都过去的事了
- Last week, we had the most amazing… - Last week was last week.
我要跟我的朋友说话好吗 有一阵没见了
I need to talk with my friend here, okay? Haven't seen her in a while.
韦斯 她病了
Wes, she's sick.
严重到只有六个月可活了
Like "six months to live" sick.
事实上 只剩五个月
Five, actually.
我得跟她好好叙叙旧 私人时间
I need to catch up with her. Private time.
好吧
Okay.
好
- 嗨 对不起 - 没关系
- Hey, I'm sorry. - That's okay.
待会见
See you around?
好的
Sure.
很抱歉让你死了一回
Sorry for killing you.
整个「只有六个月可活」的故事
The whole "six months to live" thing?
噢 对不起 是五个月
Sorry. Five.
你接茬技能也是很棒
Five was a nice touch.
- 凯丽 - 约克夏
- Kelly. - Yorkie.
- 尤基 - 约克夏
- Yurgie? - Yorkie.
约克夏狗的约克夏吗
Like the dog breed?
嗯
Yeah.
他人不坏 我觉得自己还挺过分
He's not a bad guy. I feel kinda bad.
- 在泥潭碰见他的 - 泥潭是什么
- Met him at the Quagmire so… - What's the Quagmire?
如果你不知道那里
If you don't already know what the Quagmire is,
估计你也不会想知道的
you probably don't wanna know.
是吗
No?
再来一杯吗
You want another one?
- 噢 不 我 - 哈 你要的 来吧
- Oh, no, I… - Yeah, you do. Come on.
非得牵着你的绳才走吗
Do I have to tug your leash?
- 嗨 金发女郎 - 你瞎吗
- Hey, Blondie. - I'm Blondie?
没错 喊的就是你 威士忌可乐两杯
You are. Jack and Coke times two.
- 噢 不 我的那份只要可乐 - 两杯
- Oh, no. Mine was just a Coke. - Times two.
- 你做什么 - 我在 打量你
- What are you doing? - I'm… regarding you.
我觉得我在被监测呢
I feel like I'm being analysed.
- 为什么戴眼镜 - 呃
- Why the glasses? - Um…
我喜欢 很衬你 但你视力不好吗
I like them. They totally work on you. But do you need them?
- 没有 镜片没有度数的 - 我就知道
- Yeah, the lenses don't do anything. - Knew it!
以前在学校的时候我就戴着
I used to wear them in school.
所以我觉得现在眼镜其实是一种慰藉吧
So I guess now they're just kind of a… comfort thing.
我看倒像是种时尚
I figured they were kind of a fashion statement.
- 真的吗 - 但你其他的装扮又不时尚
- Really? - But then the rest of your outfit is not.
别误会 很别具一格 我的意思是 你看看周围
Don't take that wrong. It's refreshing. I mean, look around.
人们竭尽全力将自己伪装成想象中的样子
People try so hard to look how they think they should look.
大概都是电影里看来的
They probably saw it in some movie.
但我喜欢你的打扮
But I like these.
忠于最本真的自己
You're authentically you.
谢谢
Thanks.
干杯
Cheers.
你从没喝过酒吗
You never tasted it before?
不是 我
No, I…
我只是有一阵没喝了 倒是挺好喝的
I just haven't had it in a while. It's good.
你在这生活吗
Do you live here?
- 不 呃 - 游客吗
- No. Oh, uh… - Tourist?
就当你游客吧 所以是第一次来吗
We'll go with tourist. So you're new here?
- 第一夜 - 哇 第一夜 好吧
- First night. - First night? Wow, okay!
我的天哪
Oh, my God!
这音乐我们一定得舞上一曲
We have to dance to this.
- 咱俩吗 - 嗯哼
- With each other? - Uh-huh.
- 噢不 我不是那种会跳舞的人 - 嘿 我们别给自己瞎定义好伐
- Oh, no. Dance floors aren't my thing. - Oh, let's not limit ourselves.
- 不 我不行的 - 你可以的 来吧
- No, I can't. - Yes, you can, come on.
- 不 我会看上去很傻的 - 我带着你就行
- No, I'll look dumb… - Just follow my lead!
∮ 你名字叫帕蒂 现在又说是凯 ∮
∮ Your name was Patty, but now it's Kay ∮
∮ 女孩 你怎么每天都在换名字 ∮
∮ Girl, you seem to change it every day ∮
跟着我学
Copy me.
∮ 但现在变短了 你说∮
∮ But now it's short, you say ∮
∮ 我剪短了发 但是地板上却什么发也没看见 ∮
∮ I got it cut, but I don't see no hair upon the floor ∮
很好
You got it.
∮ 每当我和你出去 ∮
∮ Whenever I go out with you ∮
∮ 我都会有新的发现 ∮
∮ I find out something new ∮
∮ 宝贝 你是个骗子 ∮
∮ You're a fake, baby ∮
∮ 你没法掩盖的 ∮
∮ You can't conceal it ∮
∮ 我知道是因为我感觉到了 ∮
∮ Know how I know 'cause I can feel it ∮
∮ 你是个骗子 宝贝 ∮
∮ You're a fake, baby… ∮
嘿
Hey!
- 你怎么跑了 - 噢对不起
- Why did you run away? - Oh, sorry.
我 我说过 我不太会跳舞
I… I said I'm not much of a dancer.
少胡扯
No shit.
刚刚你就像冰面上手足无措的小马一样
Like a frightened horse on a frozen lake back there.
开玩笑啦 也不全是玩笑啦
I'm kidding. Half kidding.
很抱歉我强迫你跳舞
Sorry I pushed you into it.
每周一次的周末之夜 时不我待 我就变得有些不耐烦
Saturday nights once a week. It's like no time. I get impatient.
不不 不是这样的 是
No, no, it's not that. It's…
- 每个人都在看我们 - 看我们吗
- Everyone was looking. - Looking?
对 看两个女孩在跳舞
Yeah. You know, two girls dancing.
好吧 首先 人们已经不像从前那么拘谨了
Okay, one, folks are way less uptight than they used to be.
再者 这是派对小城 没人会去评头论足
And two, this is a party town. No one's judging.
承认吧 即使他们在盯着看 也是因为我舞姿曼妙
Face it. If they were staring, it's because I am bodacious.
- 傻缺 - 谢谢哈
- You're stupid. - Thank you!
- 我从来没进过舞池 - 从来没有吗
- I've never been on a dance floor. - Never?
你活了这么久 从来没有吗
As in the whole time you've been alive never?
没有
Never.
你是什么物种啊 阿米什人吗
What are you, like, Amish?
你还真是稀缺物种呢
That's one sheltered existence you got there.
嗯 是啊
Yeah, well.
我家人什么都不让我做
As far as my family's concerned, I can't do anything.
哈哈 我做的烂事可都是瞒着家人的
Well, no one knows about even half the shit I get up to.
但是你们这样的家伙 一定都来自爱意满满的家庭吧
With your folks, though, it's from a place of love, though, right?
- 他们会担心 - 他们才不担心
- They worry. - They don't worry.
想到我开开心心的 他们都会受不了
Just the concept of me enjoying myself would blow their minds.
你想做什么呢 有什么是你没做过却想做的事情
What would you like to do? That you've never done?
哦
Oh…
好多好多
So many things.
圣胡尼佩罗可是座派对小城
San Junipero is a party town.
来者有份哦
All up for grabs.
还有两个小时才午夜
Midnight's two hours away.
啊 快了啊
Oh, that's not long.
那为什么要坐这里耗费人生呢
Why waste time sitting here?
我 啊
I, um…
- 听着 - 没事的
- Listen… - It's okay.
- 不 我是说 - 真的 没事
- No, I mean… - Really, it's okay.
不 我 啊 我订婚了 我有未婚夫
No, I'm, uh… I'm engaged. I have a fiancé.
- 他叫格雷格 - 格雷格在这里吗
- He's called Greg. - And is Greg here?
- 不 他在 - 别处
- No, he's… - Elsewhere?
是啊
Yeah.
哦
Oh.
想和我上床吗
Wanna go to bed with me?
我住的地方离这很近
We could be back at mine in like…
我以前都没这样过
I never did anything like that.
所以才要体验一下
All the more reason.
哦 你是个好人
Oh, you're nice.
- 我不能 - 好吧
- I can't. - Okay.
- 我 真的 不能 - 我明白
- I just… I can't. - I get it.
- 我得走了 - 冒雨走吗
- I have to go. - In this?
很高兴认识你
It's been really great to meet you.
我也是
Likewise.
好
Okay.
好的
没事
Okay.
操
Shit.
（一周后）
∮ 女友处于昏迷状态 我知道 ∮
∮ Girlfriend in a coma, I know, I know, it's… ∮
∮ 我将独自一人 ∮
∮ I'll be alone… ∮
∮ 爱人的影子翩翩起舞 ∮
∮ The shadow of a lover goes dancing by… ∮
∮ 你对爱情上瘾 ∮
∮ You're addicted to love ∮
∮ 还是承认吧 你对爱情上瘾 ∮
∮ Might as well face it you're addicted to love ∮
∮ 还是承认吧 ∮
∮ Might as well… ∮
∮ 我许愿得到爱情 得到能亲吻和倾诉的许愿井 ∮
∮ Wish me love a wishing well to kiss and tell ∮
∮ 蝴蝶之泪的许愿井 ∮
∮ A wishing well of butterfly tear ∮
∮ 我许愿得到爱情 得到能亲吻和倾诉的许愿井 ∮
∮ Wish me love a wishing well to kiss and tell ∮
∮ 鳄鱼之悦的许愿井 唱吧 ∮
∮ A wishing well of crocodile cheers, sing ∮
- 什么鬼 韦斯 - 听着 我知道我过界了
- What the hell, Wes? - Look, I know I'm coming across…
- 我要亮红灯举报你了 没开玩笑 好嘛 - 不 不要这样
- I'm red lighting you, for real. Okay? - No, don't do that. Just…
- 那就别跟着我了 - 你能听我说完吗 求你了
- Then stop this. - Can you hear me out? Please? Please.
你觉得圣胡尼佩罗有多少女孩
How many girls do you think there are in San Junipero?
几百个 几千个
Hundreds? Thousands?
管我什么事
I don't care.
我是说 天涯何处无芳草 韦斯
I'm saying there's plenty of other girls out there for you, Wes.
本地女孩吗 她们都死气沉沉的
The locals? They're like dead people.
看起来可不像哦
A little lively for dead people.
听着 我不想要无趣的浪漫 好吗
Look, I don't want some kind of boring romance, okay?
老天爷 那跟把我们放在养老院什么区别
Like, Jesus, put us in a retirement home deal.
你要是想找人打炮 选择多得很
Well, if you're looking for someone to fuck, there's options.
- 再去泥潭转转 - 我们不只是炮友啊
- Hang out at the Quagmire again. - It's not just sex.
- 我们就是炮友 - 不 我们心有灵犀的
- It was just sex. - No, we made a connection.
韦斯 我们只是炮友
Wes, it was just sex.
- 不 - 我们没结果的
- No… - No roots.
一时欢愉
We had fun.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
你至少可以在城里好好玩玩啊
Enjoy the town, for God's sake.
- 嘿 - 嘿
- Hey. - Hey.
等人吗
Waiting for someone?
没有
Not really.
能给你买杯喝的吗
I'll get you a drink?
啊 好啊 没问题
Uh, yeah, sure.
所以 啊 是啊 就是个微型手术 大概吧
So, uh… yeah, it was microsurgery, I guess.
你知道 我的两个膝盖都有磨损了
You know, both my kneecaps had kind of just worn down.
话说 我从来没懂过这首歌 有点奇怪
You know, I never got this song. Kind of weird.
- 咱们跳个舞吧 - 好啊
- Shall we dance? - Sure.
∮ 我们只有当下 ∮
∮ All we've got is this moment ∮
∮ 21世纪已是陈年旧事 ∮
∮ The 21st century's yesterday ∮
我想到时候我该专心于电脑运算了
I mean, I guess by the time I'd put my mind to, like, computing.
抢占先机 故事就得另说了
You know, caught that first wave, would have had a different story.
去下洗手间
Gotta use the bathroom.
好
Okay.
- 我不知道要怎么办 - 什么怎么办
- I don't know how to do this. - Do what?
帮帮我
Just help me.
你能不能
Can you just…
让我好过些
Just make this easy for me?
想去我车兜兜风吗
You wanna get in my car?
- 你在这里多久了 - 什么
- How long have you been here? - Sorry?
- 你在这里多久了 - 圣胡普罗吗
- How long have you been here? - In San Junipero?
啊 几个月了 原本就是想来这放松享受的
Uh… Couple of months. Plan is long enough to enjoy myself.
看起来我也是个游客 和你一样
Guess I'm a tourist, like you.
是啊
Yeah.
嘿 你还好吗
Hey. You okay?
嗯
Yeah.
停车
Stop!
抱歉 但是
Sorry, but…
哈哈 看你表情
Man, your face!
哇哦
Wow.
- 你喜欢吗 - 好大的屋子啊
- You like it? - It's just so big.
让我想起来我长大的地方
Reminds me of where I grew up.
想你妈妈了吗
Miss your mom?
你要告诉我怎么做
You have to show me.
- 好的 - 好
- Okay. - Okay.
你从来没和女人睡过吗
You never slept with a woman before?
我没别的意思 只是想说 刚才爽翻了
That's not a critique. I mean, it was fucking awesome.
没有 没和女人睡过
No, never with a woman.
没和任何人睡过
Never with anyone.
谁都没有
Not anyone?
- 你是说 城里的 还是 - 没有 谁都没有 哪儿都没有
- What, in town or…? - No. No one, nowhere.
- 我猜你破了我的处 - 我破了你的处
- I guess you deflowered me. - I deflowered you?
怎么着 你活在旧时英格兰吗
What is this? Merry England?
闭嘴
Shut up.
但是你有谈过恋爱吧
You've had relationships though.
没有
Mnh-mnh.
喂喂 你可是有未婚夫的人
Hello! You got a fiancé.
- 说来话长 - 哈哈 我猜也是
- It's complicated. - Yeah, I'll say.
你什么时候知道
When did you know…
- 自己喜欢女人的 - 我也喜欢男人啊
- that you liked women? - I like men too.
平等的权利
Equal rights.
好的
Okay.
但你是什么时候知道
But when did you know?
你一直知道吗
Do you always know?
之前我和一个男人结了婚 婚姻持续了很长一段时间
I was married to a guy. A long time, I was married.
我一直都知道
I always knew.
我是说 我总是被其它的女孩子吸引
I mean, I'd be attracted to other girls,
同事 朋友 一些给我服务过的女服务员
co-workers, friends, some waitress that served me.
她们都令我着迷 哦天 她们都如此迷人
They were crushes. God, they were crushes.
但我从没有采取过行动
Never acted on any of it.
没有任何行动
Never did anything.
我和他相爱过
I was in love with him.
我是真的爱过他
I really was in love with him.
但他选择离开我
But he chose not to stick around.
现在换我了 我来这溜达会
So now it's me. And I'm passing through.
在我离开前 一定会玩得开心
And before I leave, I'll have a good time.
我会玩得很开心
I'm just gonna have a good time.
时间快到了
Time's nearly up.
那就让我们躺在这儿
Then let's lie here.
（一周后）
打扰一下
Excuse me?
你看到凯丽了吗
Have you seen Kelly?
- 什么 - 凯利
- What's that? - Kelly.
我一整晚都没见到她
I haven't seen her all night.
你去泥潭看过了吗
You tried the Quagmire?
泥潭是什么
What is the Quagmire?
- 哇 嘿 - 对不起
- Whoa! Hey! - I'm sorry!
嗯 我好像在哪见过你
Yeah, I know you from somewhere.
塔克家里
Tucker's.
- 凯丽的朋友吗 - 你知道到哪儿能找到她吗
- Kelly's friend, huh? - Do you know where to find her?
- 我怎么会知道 - 你是她的朋友啊
- How would I know that? - You're her friend.
- 曾经是 - 她来过这里吗
- Was a friend. - Has she been here?
没有
No.
你也没有 是吗
You too, huh?
嗯
Well…
嘿 试着换个时间段
Hey. Try a different time.
这儿你可以试试80，90年代 或者2002年的某一时间段
Here in '80, the '90s, 2002 one time.
她值得一试 对吧
She's worth the shot, right?
（一周后）
完整地介绍下翻新的克莱斯勒·柯多巴
Introducing the totally redesigned Chrysler Cordoba.
在这里你能得到想要的奢华
All the luxury you expect is here.
这是一加仑的里程
But so is gas mileage…
不不不
No, no, no.
- 嘿 - 嘿
- Hey. - Hey.
黄金时代 是吧
Golden age, right?
- 是的 - 你要玩吗
- Right. - You playing or…
不好意思 我在找人
I'm sorry, I'm looking for someone.
要不然 下次
Maybe… next time.
（一周后）
凯丽
Kelly?
（一周后）
耶
Yeah!
你真美
You're beautiful!
- 选首歌 - 嗨
- Select a song! - Hi.
上洗手间
Ladies' room.
嘿
Hey.
嘿 别走 你
Hey. No, you…
等一下
Wait a minute.
你为什么会在这里
Why are you here?
我一直在找你 你去哪儿了
I was looking for you. Where did you go?
我想换首音乐
I like a change of music.
这怎么会是你的时代
How the hell is this your era?
- 你躲我 - 首先 我没有
- You hid from me. - One, I did not.
其次 我不欠你的 最后 我不欠你的
Two, I owe you zero. And three… see point two.
这不关谁欠谁的事 这是态度问题
It's not about who owes who. It's about manners.
你不知道我是谁
You don't know who I am.
你不知道这意味着什么
You don't know what this means.
这意味着欢乐
This means fun.
或者应该意味着欢乐 而且这
Or it should. And this…
一点不好玩 好吗
This is not fun, okay?
一点不好玩
This is not fun.
难道你不觉得很内疚吗
So you don't feel bad?
或许你应该觉得内疚 或至少有点感情
Maybe you should feel bad. Or at least feel something.
你见过过一个女孩子吗 二十五岁左右的样子 棕色头发 戴眼镜
Have you seen a girl? Mid-20s, brown hair, glasses?
呃
Uh…
哦天哪
Oh, jeez.
嘿
Hey.
告诉我你的痛觉弧设定为零了
Please tell me you got your pain slider set to zero.
嗯 我想是的
Yeah, I think so.
- 好的 听着 - 他们有多少人死了
- Okay, listen. - How many of them are dead?
大概的比例是多少
Like what percentage?
全时段的人群中吗
As in full-timers?
八十 八十五
Eighty. Eighty-five.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
- 我不会跳的 - 我知道 我很抱歉 不管怎么说
- I'm not gonna jump. - I know, and I'm sorry, whatever it's…
之前在这的时候 我说过我不会
In the time I've been here, I said I wouldn't…
怎么说呢 不会动感情吧
I don't know, do feelings.
你真的让我手足无措了
You freaked me out.
我不想喜欢任何人
I don't want to like anyone.
所以你的出现打乱了我的享乐
So you've been just… totally fucking inconvenient.
因为
It's that…
我不知道还有多少时间
I don't know how long there is.
而且我也不能喜欢谁 你的出现和对你的欲望都是意料之外的
And I can't. I wasn't prepared for you. For wanting something…
下一周
Next week it is.
我就要结婚了
I'm getting married.
下一周
Next week?
嫁给好人格雷格吗
To nice Greg?
- 确定了吗 - 我别无选择
- Sure you're going through with that? - I have to.
- 别无选择吗 - 嗯嗯
- You have to? - Mm-hmm.
他真的是个好人
He really is a good guy.
我家人不同意我被传送 但是
I mean, my family don't approve, but…
他们也无力阻止
they can't stop us.
我知道他同情我 这让我很生气
I know he pities me. That pisses me off.
但那也不公平 因为他
But that's not fair 'cause he's…
你说你不知道还有多少时间
You said you don't know how much time there is.
是什么意思
What does that mean?
他们告诉我三个月
They tell me three months.
癌细胞已经扩散开了
It's spread basically everywhere.
他们在九个月前就这么说的
They said three months before six months ago.
所以咯 你觉得他们真的知道很多吗
So, you know, what do they know?
甚至不知道一切是怎样的体验
Doesn't even taste of anything.
- 但你之后要留在这儿吗 - 不
- But so you'll stay here after? - No.
当我生命终结 我就死了
When I'm done, I am done.
但这太疯 我是说
But that's cra… I mean…
- 为什么 - 理查德
- Why? - Richard.
那
That's…
我丈夫的名字是理查德
My husband's name was Richard.
他两年前才死
He died just two years ago.
所以我们有过留在生胡尼佩罗的机会
So we had the opportunity to stay in San Junipero.
被传送过去
Pass over.
但我们放弃了
Didn't take it.
- 不想被传送 - 换作任何人都会接受的吧
- Didn't want to take it. - Why wouldn't anyone take it?
他有自己的想法
He had his viewpoint.
他有自己相信和不相信的事情
There were things he believed and things he didn't believe in,
这个地方就属于他不相信的事情
and this place was one of them.
连来都不会来 更不会尝试
Wouldn't even visit. Take the trial run.
唉
Shit.
我也不知道自己想不想尝试 但是
I didn't know if I wanted to try it but… I mean…
天呐 没有这里 我永远不会遇到像你这样的人
Jesus, without this place, I never would've met someone like you.
- 不 你可以的 - 不会的
- Yeah, you could have. - No, I wouldn't.
- 我们在外面依然会遇到 - 不会的
- We could have met outside all this. - No.
你 永远不会遇到我的
You… would not have got me at all.
永远
At all.
如果我们真的遇见
If we really met, I mean…
如果真的那样 你也不会喜欢我的
If we really met, you wouldn't like me.
试试看
Try me.
你不会愿意和我一起玩耍
Or you'd…You wouldn't want to spend time with me.
- 你来了之后就会 - 有本事试试
- You'd come and then… - Try me.
为什么
Why?
为什么 有什么意义
Why? What's the point?
你在哪里 休斯顿吗
What? Where are you? Houston?
我在内华达州卡森城
Carson City, Nevada.
来嘛
So come on.
我跟你说了我在哪儿
I showed you mine.
你呢
Where are you?
- 我可以去找找 - 加利福尼亚圣罗莎
- I can just look it up. - Santa Rosa, California.
- 离我不远 - 我不希望你
- That's no distance. - I don't want you to…
- 我不希望你来见我 我怕 - 我就要死了
- I don't want you to see me. I'm scared… - And I'm dying.
你无论什么样都吓不到我
Whatever you are can't scare me.
让我见见你吧
Let me come visit.
我想和你打个招呼
I want to say hi.
来吧
Here you go.
你还好吗
You okay?
请在我们的自助舱
Please check in at our self-service pods.
刷卡登记
using swipe cards provided.
- 你一定是凯丽 - 我猜我是
- You must be Kelly. - I guess I must.
- 她在等你 - 谢谢
- She's waiting for you. - Thank you.
请
Please.
她身体可能没有反应
She won't be able to physically respond in any way.
但是她能听见你说话
But she can hear you.
我给你们一些私人空间
I'll give you some privacy.
小笨笨 你好呀
Hello, stupid.
见到你真好
It's good to see you.
呃 你好 请问下 你是凯丽吗
Uh… Hello. Excuse me. Is it… Kelly?
我是
It is.
- 我是格雷格 - 你是格雷格
- I'm Greg. - You're Greg?
他妈的
Holy shit.
嗯 在她被传送之前 你能亲自来见她一面
Yeah, I think it's great that you came down here in person.
真的太好了
before she passes over.
甚至她的父母都不再来看她了 所以
Even her folks don't come visit no more so…
她要去世了吗
She's passing over?
- 什么时候 - 呃
- When? - Uh…
- 我们边喝咖啡边聊吧 - 好的
- Let's go grab a coffee. - Okay.
- 她没告诉你吗 - 没有
- She didn't tell you? - No, she did not.
- 她只说自己是去玩玩的 - 更像一个试用版
- Said she was just visiting. - More like sampling the trial version.
我的意思是 我和她相识才三年
I mean, I've only known her the past three years.
我们在通讯箱里聊天
We talk on the comm box.
她告诉你她是怎样成为植物人了吗
She told you how she ended up quadriplegic?
还有她这样多久了
And how long she's been that way?
她21岁的一个晚上 她向父母出柜了
One night, she's 21, comes out to her folks.
他们对此有些恼火
They're a little uptight about it, you might say.
告诉她 他们不想要一个同性恋女儿
They told her they don't want a gay daughter.
因为那不正常 之类的
It's not natural and so forth.
他们吵了一架 她开车的时候偏离了道路 然后邦的一声
They fight. She gets in her car. Runs it off the road. Boom!
- 她那时才21 - 40多年前的事了
- When she was 21? - More than 40 years back.
基本上她是这样过了一辈子
It's been her whole lifetime, basically.
所以整个生胡尼佩罗系统对她来说很重要
So the whole San Junipero system has been a big deal for her.
最重要的
The biggest deal.
她被传送之后 就能永远待那了
Of course now, until she passes over, it goes permanent,
而之前 她每个星期只有5个小时的时间
she's on a five-hour weekly limit.
我猜你也一样
I guess you're the same.
这时间是他们按量分的 也不愿意再多加些时间
They ration it out. They don't trust us with more.
他们说时间太久你会疯掉的
They say you go crazy if you have too much, you know?
你长时间坐着 精神和肉体分离
You don't leave your seat. You disassociate body from mind.
这本就是老年之家里的常态
Like that doesn't happen in every senior home already.
系统存在的主要意义是为了治疗
The system's there for therapeutic reasons,
身临其境的怀旧疗法
immersive nostalgia therapy.
让你浸入到记忆的深海里
Plunge you into a world of memories.
他们说这有助于老年痴呆患者
Helps with Alzheimer's, that's what they say.
小小的仁慈
Small mercies.
那么
So…
这桩婚事
About this marriage…
对于执行安乐死 国家规定需要三层授权
The state's got a triple lockdown on euthanasia cases.
需要医生 病人和一个家庭成员签字
You gotta have a sign-off from the doc, the patient, a family member.
以避免人们为了待在圣胡尼佩罗 选择死亡
It's to stop folks from passing over just because they prefer San Junipero flat out.
但是约克夏的家人
Anyhow, Yorkie's family,
他们都是非常虔诚的宗教主义者 所以肯定不会签字
they're big-time religious, and they will not sign.
但是配偶的权利可以超越他们
But a spouse can override them.
- 所以你们才决定结婚 - 没错
- Hence the wedding bells. - You got it.
明天上午会有一个牧师过来
We got a pastor coming tomorrow A.M.,
她的传送被排在下午
and then she's scheduled to pass tomorrow afternoon.
计划传送 还是说她时日不多了吧
"Scheduled to pass." Let's just call it dying.
要是你愿意的话
If you can call it dying.
将她的记忆传至云端 听起来就像是去了天堂
Uploaded to the cloud, sounds like heaven.
是吧
I guess.
你会穿礼服吗
You gonna wear a suit?
结婚仪式就在我休息的时候举办
The ceremony's on my coffee break.
我没结过婚 所以我想 有什么所谓呢
I never married so I just figured, you know, what's the harm?
你是个好人
You're a good man.
这不足挂齿 不是吗
It's the least I could do, right?
你现在能帮我们连接到系统中吗
Think you could hook us up to the system now?
在她被传送之前 就小一会儿
Just for a little while, before she passes?
你以后还能见到她 我是说 那时候她就一直在那了
You can still see her afterwards. I mean, then she's no limit.
她那时候就是个全职的圣胡尼佩罗胖子了
She's full, fat, permanent San Juniperan.
我知道 但是你能不能帮我们
I know, but can you?
说真的 这里看得很紧 监视器到处
Seriously, it is so tight here that they monitor every…
我只需要一会儿
I only want a moment.
女士
Ma'am.
- 给你们5分钟 - 谢谢
- You got five minutes. - Thank you.
嘿
Hey!
我从来没在白天来过
I've never been here during the daylight.
很暖和
It's warm.
听着 我得快点说 我刚和格雷格聊过了
Listen, I gotta be quick. So I spoke to Greg.
奥
Oh.
- 你打算明天走 - 是
- You're passing over tomorrow? - Yeah.
婚礼过后几个小时
Couple of hours after the wedding.
所以我猜 理论上来说我将永远在这里度蜜月了
So I guess I am technically honeymooning here forever.
很抱歉我没告诉你
I'm sorry I didn't tell you.
- 我接下来的话可能会有些疯狂 - 好
- I'm gonna say something crazy. - Okay.
跟我结婚吧
Wanna marry me instead?
那个 格雷格看起来不错 但是
It's just… Greg seems great, but…
为什么不嫁给和你心心牵挂的人呢
Why not someone you've connected with?
这是答应了吗
Is that a yes?
和你合法的妻子
…to be your lawfully wedded wife,
相爱相守 无论疾病还是健康
to have and to hold, in sickness and in health,
不论是好是坏 富裕或贫穷
in good times and in woe, for richer, for poorer…
抓稳了
Hold tight.
好了
There you go.
马上就到了
Nearly there.
没错
That's it.
你确定你没事吗
Are you sure you're all right?
嘿
Hey!
你来见我都不打扮一下吗
You didn't dress up to see me?
哦
Oh…
行不行啊
Come on!
好点了吗
Better?
啊
Whoop!
哦
Oh!
哦 哇
Oh! Whoo!
看起来好真实啊
Looks so real.
感觉好真实啊
It feels so real!
- 你干什么呢 - 哦 我好喜欢这里啊
- What are you doing? - Oh, I love it here!
我好喜欢啊
I just love it.
- 你以前也来过啊 - 但是现在我住在这里了
- You've been here before. - But now I live here!
和我在一起
Be with me.
- 我现在就和你在一起 - 我说的不是这个
- I'm with you now. - That's not what I mean.
传送过来吧
Pass over.
- 当你寿命将尽的时候 - 约克夏
- When it's your time. - Yorkie.
- 留下来陪我 - 我们不能只享受现在嘛
- Stay here with me. - Can we just enjoy tonight?
已经快半夜了
It's almost midnight.
还有十分钟 你就要走了
In ten minutes, you're out of here.
我就要等一周才能再见到你
Then I gotta wait a week to see you again.
- 你知道我只是游客 - 那 几个月之后呢 会怎么样
- You know I'm just a visitor. - What, a couple of months, then what?
- 我们别讨论这个 - 之后你就走了
- We're not discussing this. - Then you're gone.
- 你就不存在了 你本可以永生的 - 永生吗
- Just gone. You could have forever. - Forever?
- 谁能定义永生 - 依你所想 多久都可以
- Who can even make sense of forever? - However long you want then.
我是说 你那样就可以永远拜托自己的难题了
I mean, you can remove yourself like that.
又不是陷阱
It's not a trap.
我是说 你看看啊 天哪 你摸一下
I mean, look at it! Jesus! Touch it!
- 我要走了 - 嘿 哦 嘿
- I'm going. - Hey! Oh. Hey.
这是真的
It's real.
这是真实的
This is real.
还有这个
And this.
- 嗯 - 别骗自己了
- Hmm? - Come on.
你知道那只是个手势
You know that was just a gesture.
- 你娶了我 - 那是为了给你最后的慰藉
- You married me. - To help you pass over.
- 是一种善意 - 那你离开可就不善意了
- As a… Kindness. - It's not so kind to leave.
好吧 听着 听着 我很抱歉 我只是
Okay, look, look, I'm sorry, I just…
我有了这次机会
I got this chance.
我们有了这次机会 我想和你一起分享
We got this chance. I wanna share it with you.
我已经决定了
I said I made my choice.
为什么 你愧疚是因为你老公不在吗
What is it? You feel bad because your husband isn't here?
- 因为那是他的选择 - 别
- Because that was his choice. - Don't.
他没有选择留在这 就和离开你没有区别
He chose not to stay here. It's like he left you.
你知道 他可以选择留下 但是他选择了离开你
You know, he could have stayed, but he chose to leave you.
- 你在胡言乱语 - 你应该生他的气才对
- You don't know what you're saying. - You should be mad at him.
- 而不是拿内疚惩罚自己 - 离我远点
- Not whipping yourself with guilt. - Get off me.
你看不清 但是他的所作所为都很自私
You can't see it! But what he did, it was selfish actually!
四十九年
Forty-nine years…
我和他在一起四49年
I was with him for 49 years.
你根本无法想象
You can't begin to imagine.
你根本不知道
You can't know…
我们之间的纽带 承诺 繁琐
the bond, the commitment, the boredom,
渴望 欢笑 爱情
the yearning, the laughter, the love of it.
我们之间的爱情 你根本无法体会
The fucking love. You just cannot know!
我们牺牲的所有
Everything we sacrificed.
我们互相陪伴的日子
The years I gave him. The years he gave me.
你有想过要问问吗
Did you think to ask?
Did it occur to you to ask?
我们有个女儿
We had a daughter.
艾莉森
Alison.
难伺候的美丽小公主
Always difficult, always beautiful.
39岁就死了 望她安息
Died at 39 years old, bless her heart.
理查德和我心如刀割
And Richard and I, we felt that heartbreak as one.
你以为只有是你才受过罪 滚你丫的
You think you're the only person ever suffered, go fuck yourself.
- 嗯 我不知道 - 是根本没想过吧
- Well, I didn't know… - Didn't think to.
你知道吗 理查德死前和我说
You know, when he was dying, Richard said to me.
他们当时给他这个选择 死后被传送
when they offered him this, to pass over, pass through,
在你热爱的这个操蛋墓地里永生
spend eternity in this fucking graveyard you're so in love with,
他回答的是 「我怎么能选择永生 她错失了这样的机会之后 我怎么能选择永生」
he said, "How can I? When she missed out, how can I?"
所以他真正地去世了
And so he went.
我倒是希望能让自己相信 他在陪着她
And I wish I could believe he's with her now,
他们在一起 但是我做不到
that they're together, but I don't.
我相信他们不存在了 就和你说的一样
I believe they're nowhere. Just like you said.
不在了 不 我同情你 真相就是 我同情你
Gone. No, I pitied you, and that's the truth. I pitied you.
现在你却在这里告诉我
Now you give me some sales pitch.
操蛋的永恒有多么完美
about how fucking peachy forever could be.
真抱歉
I'm sorry.
你是想永远生活在一个毫无激情的地方吗
You wanna spend forever somewhere nothing matters?
最后落得和韦斯
End up like Wes?
和那些迷失在泥潭的渣滓一样
All those lost fucks at the Quagmire.
用尽力气只为感受点激情 那走好不送
trying anything to feel something, go ahead.
但是恕不奉陪 我走了
But I'm out. I'm gone.
凯丽 对不起 凯丽
Kelly, I'm sorry. Kelly!
嘿 凯丽
Hey, Kelly.
- 你没事吧 - 嗯 我没事
- You all right? - Yeah, I am fine.
- 嗯 那好吧 - 什么
- Well, okay then. - Huh?
凯丽
Kelly?
我考虑了所有的事情
All things considered…
我想我准备好了
I guess I'm ready.
什么准备好了
For what?
余生
For the rest of it.
∮ 噢 亲爱的 你知道它的价值吗 ∮
∮ Ooh, baby, do you know what that's worth ∮
∮ 哦 天堂就在人间 ∮
∮ Ooh, heaven is a place on Earth ∮
∮ 他们说，在天堂爱情至上 ∮
∮ They say in heaven love comes first ∮
∮ 我们将在这人间造出一个天堂 ∮
∮ We'll make heaven a place on Earth ∮
∮ 哦 天堂就在人间 ∮
∮ Ooh, heaven is a place on Earth ∮
∮ 当我感到孤独时 ∮
∮ When I feel alone ∮
∮ 我偎依在你身旁 ∮
∮ I reach for you ∮
∮ 你要带我回家 ∮
∮ And you bring me home ∮
∮ 我迷失在那片海 ∮
∮ When I'm lost at sea ∮
∮ 我听到你的声音 让我继续前行 ∮
∮ I hear your voice and it carries me ∮
准备好了吗
Ready?
- ∮ 在这个世界我们才刚刚开始 ∮ - 哇哦
- ∮ In this world we're just beginning ∮ - Whoo!
∮ 去理解这生命的奇迹 ∮
∮ To understand the miracle of living ∮
- ∮ 我只是不够勇敢 ∮ - 哇哦
- ∮ Maybe I wasn't brave before ∮ - Whoo!
∮ 但我已无所畏惧 ∮
∮ But I'm not afraid anymore ∮
∮ 噢 宝贝 你可知道这可值得 ∮
∮ Ooh, baby, do you know what that's worth ∮
∮ 哦 天堂就在人间 ∮
∮ Ooh, heaven is a place on Earth ∮
∮ 他们说，在天堂爱情至上 ∮
∮ They say in heaven love comes first ∮
∮ 我们将在这人间造出一个天堂 ∮
∮ We'll make a heaven a place on Earth ∮
∮ 哦 天堂就在人间 ∮
∮ Ooh, heaven is a place on Earth ∮
∮ 天堂 ∮
∮ Heaven ∮
∮ 在这个世界我们才刚刚开始 ∮
∮ In this world, we're just beginning ∮
∮ 去理解这生命的奇迹 ∮
∮ To understand the miracle of living ∮
∮ 宝贝我曾惊恐万分 ∮
∮ Baby, I was afraid before ∮
∮ 但我已无所畏惧 ∮
∮ I'm not afraid anymore ∮